# Ramesh Ojha

Having 6+ years of experience in programming (mostly in front-end), and I am looking for a good opportunity where I can enhance my core skills. I also have an engineering degree and have good knowledge of computer science and information technologies. Currently pursuing master's course from online distance education.

# **Work Experience**

## Senior Software Engineer, Coforge Limited

Dec 2023 - Present

- Worked on complicated screens development with approximately 10-15 API calls on single page.
- Did R&D, POC and implementation of Dark Mode from scratch.
- Followed test driven development approach for repo migration.
- Worked on technologies like NextJS, ReactJS, Redux, NodeJS, Axios, MUI, Storybook, Jest (RTL), HTML, SCSS, GIT and AWS.

## **Solution Engineer, Degode**

Jun 2021 - Dec 2023

- Did R&D, POC and implementation of whitelabeling in the legacy project based on automated chat-support application.
- Debugged production level bugs and resolved it in quick time.
- Created atomic and molecular components for UI in ReactJS.
- Have implemented servers and connected it to database.
- Worked on TypeScript, NextJS, ReactJS, Redux, ExpressJS, MongoDB, GrapghQL, Socket.io, GIT, Jenkins and AWS.

## **Junior Developer, Arikaptics**

Nov 2018 - Apr 2021

- Contributed in development of e-commerce application supporting accounting.
- Wrote CRUD operations queries for database.
- Implemented auth using JWT menthod.
- Technologies used ReactJS, TypeScript, Redux, ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, TypeORM, Axios, REST and GIT.

## **Educational Background**

## Master of Computer Application (MCA) (Pursuing Currently)

Indra Gandhi National Open University Jan 2023 - Present

· Learning DSA, ML, AI, Python and System Design.

## **Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering**

Dr. A.P.J Abdul Kalam Technical University Aug 2013 - Jul 2018

• Got exposure to C, C++, HTML and CSS.

#### Contact

Noida Sector 59 +91-9540205885 ramstartwork@gmail.com www.rameshojha.com leetcode - rameshojha3131

## **Skills**

#### Frontend Skills

- NextJS, ReactJS, Redux
- HTML, CSS, SCSS
- JavaScript, TypeScript

#### **Backend Skills**

- ExpressJS
- MongoDB, TypeORM
- Python

#### **Additional Skills**

- · AWS, Jenkins, Vercel, ArgoCD
- Jest, RTL, Enzyme
- Python

## **Certification/Short Courses**

- · Responsive Web Designing
- Javascript Algorithm & Data Structure
- Frontend Development Libraries
- NextJs
- Advanced React & Storybook

#### **Additional Information**

- Managing 2-3 Junior Developers in my current project.
- Participate in extra curricular activites and campus sports competition.